Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we've got a very advanced dialogue for you.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一段非常高级的对话。
This is all about what we call the miracle of life.
这完全是关于我们所说的生命奇迹。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to talk a little bit more in depth about our bodies, about what's going
今天我们要更深入地谈谈我们的身体，
on inside and how and where babies come from.
关于身体内部发生了什么，以及婴儿从哪里来。
That's right.
没错。
So you're going to learn very technical terms for parts of people's bodies, men and women,
所以你们会学到关于人体部位、男性和女性的非常专业的术语，
and also about the beginning of life.
还有关于生命的起源。
So before a baby is born, what do you call some of these parts and some of these things?
那么在婴儿出生之前，这些部位和这些东西叫什么？
So let's check out today's dialogue and when we come back, we'll be exploring in depth
所以让我们来看看今天的对话，等我们回来时，
these topics.
我们会深入探讨这些话题。
Continuing with our class, today we are going to study briefly the miracle of life.
继续我们的课程，今天我们要简要地学习生命的奇迹。
Many of you may think you already know how babies come to be, but I'm sure that some
你们很多人可能觉得自己已经知道婴儿是怎么来的，但我相信
of the things we will be talking about today may surprise you.
我们今天要讲的一些事情可能会让你们惊讶。
Billy, can you turn on the projector please?
Billy，你能打开投影仪吗？
Thanks.
谢谢。
Okay.
好的。
Does anyone know what this is?
有人知道这是什么吗？
Looks like a goat head to me.
在我看来像个山羊头。
Nice try.
猜得不错。
But this is a woman's womb, which contains her uterus and ovaries.
但这是女性的子宫，里面包含子宫和卵巢。
The ovaries are packed with eggs and each month during the middle of the menstrual cycle,
卵巢里装满了卵子，每个月在月经周期的中期，
the ripest one will be sucked up by one of the fallopian tubes.
最成熟的那个会被一根输卵管吸走。
This is called ovulation and the exact time of ovulation depends on the length of a woman's
这叫做排卵，而排卵的具体时间取决于女性
cycle.
周期的长度。
In an average 28-day cycle, ovulation will most likely happen between the 12th and 15th
在一个平均28天的周期中，排卵最可能发生在第12到第15天之间，
days, counting day one as the first day of your last period.
把第一天算作你上次月经的第一天。
That's amazing!
太神奇了！
So each month, the woman produces these eggs and then waits for them to be fertilized?
所以每个月，女性产生这些卵子，然后等待它们被受精？
Actually every woman is already born with over 400,000 eggs.
实际上，每个女性出生时就已经有超过40万个卵子。
Some will start dying off immediately and others are released during her fertile period.
有些会立即开始死亡，其他的则在她生育期释放出来。
What about the guys?
那男的呢？
I know they produce sperm and stuff.
我知道他们产生精子和之类的东西。
That's right.
没错。
The man's body has a tiny factory that produces sperm 24 hours a day.
男性的身体有一个小工厂，每天24小时生产精子。
Each ejaculation will release about 100 million sperm, so the factory is always pretty busy.
每次射精会释放大约1亿个精子，所以这个工厂总是很忙。
The sole purpose of a sperm's life is to fertilize the woman's egg.
精子生命的唯一目的就是使女性的卵子受精。
So then we basically need to put one and one together so we can have babies, right?
那么基本上我们需要把一和加在一起才能有孩子，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
Some will have an orgasm during intercourse and ejaculate sperm and semen.
有些人在性交时会达到高潮并射出精子和精液。
Now this is where the race begins and all those millions of sperm will race and swim
现在这就是赛跑开始的地方，那数百万个精子会赛跑并游动
from the cervix through the uterus and to the fallopian tubes.
从子宫颈穿过子宫到达输卵管。
This could take anywhere from 45 minutes to 12 hours.
这可能需要45分钟到12小时不等。
Not all of them make it since some of them go the wrong way and get lost or simply die.
不是所有精子都能成功，因为有些走错了方向迷路了，或者干脆死掉了。
Many will actually reach the egg but only one will penetrate it and fertilize it.
很多精子会到达卵子，但只有一个能穿透并使其受精。
As this happens, the egg instantly changes and creates a protective shield once the sperm
当这发生时，卵子会立即改变，并在精子
is safely inside.
安全进入后形成一个保护屏障。
And then that's it?
然后就这样了？
Well the egg will be fertilized within about 24 hours of its release.
嗯，卵子会在释放后大约24小时内受精。
The genetic material from the sperm combines with the genetic material in the egg to create
来自精子的遗传物质与卵子中的遗传物质结合，形成
a new cell that will rapidly start dividing.
一个新细胞，它会迅速开始分裂。
The woman is not actually pregnant until that bundle of new cells known as the embryo travels
女性实际上直到那团新细胞——称为胚胎——沿着输卵管
the rest of the way down the fallopian tube and attaches itself to the wall of her uterus.
继续下行并附着在子宫壁上时，才算真正怀孕。
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
Then let's move on.
那我们继续。
All right we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So very interesting.
非常有趣。
Actually this type of lecture or class that we just saw is very common in biology class
实际上，我们刚才看到的这种讲座或课程，在美国的生物课
or anatomy class in the US for example.
或解剖课上很常见。
That's right.
没错。
We have a class called sex ed or sexual education and this is all about sex and bodies and biology
我们有一门课叫性教育，这全是关于性、身体和生物学，
that most students have to learn before they go into high school.
大多数学生在进入高中之前都必须学习。
That's right.
没错。
So we actually had a previous lesson about sex ed.
所以我们之前其实有一节关于性教育的课。
We talked about contraceptives and while continuing on the topic, this is why we have this advanced
我们讨论了避孕药具，而继续这个话题，这就是为什么我们现在有这节高级
lesson now.
课程。
It is a little bit more difficult because we have medical terms and specific names of
这有点难，因为我们有医学术语和身体内部部位的具体名称。
parts inside of our body.
So why don't we start with the first one when the teacher explained about a woman's womb.
所以我们不如从第一个开始，当老师解释女性的子宫时。
So this might look like a very hard word to pronounce.
这看起来可能是个很难发音的词。
There's a B there.
里面有个B。
So W-O-M-B.
所以是W-O-M-B。
We don't pronounce womb.
我们不读成“womb”。
We say womb.
我们读成“womb”。
This is basically where the baby will grow when a baby is produced.
这基本上就是婴儿产生时生长的地方。
So it's a part inside a woman's body that we also call the uterus.
所以它是女性身体内部的一部分，我们也称之为子宫。
So I guess the uterus is the specific name of that area, right?
所以我猜子宫是那个区域的具体名称，对吧？
But I guess the whole thing, kind of like the woman's belly where the baby is going
但我猜整个东西，有点像女性怀孕时婴儿所在的肚子。
to be, is called the womb.
存在，被称为子宫。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So now taking a look at other parts of a woman's body, we have the womb, we have the uterus.
那么现在来看女性身体的其他部分，我们有子宫，也就是子宫。
Now what about the ovaries?
那卵巢呢？
So ovaries are, actually there are two of them in a woman's body and ovaries are where
卵巢，实际上女性体内有两个卵巢，卵巢是
eggs are stored.
储存卵子的地方。
So women have eggs and this is what will one day become, in some cases, a baby.
所以女性有卵子，这些卵子将来在某些情况下会变成婴儿。
And so they are stored in ovaries and when it's time to come down, they come down through
它们储存在卵巢里，当需要排出时，它们会通过
the uterus, through these tubes to either come out or to be met by a sperm.
子宫，经过这些管道要么排出体外，要么与精子相遇。
Right.
对。
And these tubes are actually called fallopian tubes.
这些管道实际上叫做输卵管。
So a hard word, fallopian.
一个难读的词，输卵管。
Again, there are two of these, right, one from each ovary and they come down and that's
同样，有两个这样的管道，对吧，每个卵巢各一个，它们向下延伸，这基本上
basically a passageway for eggs.
是卵子的通道。
That's right.
没错。
And it's interesting because in English, some women that don't want to have any more kids,
有趣的是，在英语中，一些不想再生孩子的女性
they very colloquially say, I have my tubes tied or I had my tubes tied.
会非常口语化地说，“我扎了管子”或“我扎过管子”。
That's right.
没错。
So this means a woman has had an operation so that she will not have children in the
这意味着女性做了手术，这样她将来就不会有孩子，
future and her fallopian tubes are closed off so that eggs cannot come down.
她的输卵管被封闭，卵子无法排出。
That's right.
没错。
And this is kind of now you more or less, if you've heard this phrase before, now you
现在你或多或少，如果你以前听过这个说法，现在你
understand why the fallopian tubes and that's why women say tubes tied.
就明白为什么是输卵管，以及为什么女性说“扎管子”。
Yeah, she had her tubes tied.
是的，她扎了管子。
All right.
好的。
So now all of this is going on because, well, a woman can potentially get pregnant and during
那么所有这些发生是因为，嗯，女性有可能怀孕，在这段
this period of time, this is when the woman is ovulating or this is called ovulation.
时间里，就是女性排卵的时候，或者这叫做排卵期。
That's right.
没错。
So ovulation is a cycle that means it's something that happens again and again and again.
所以排卵是一个周期，意味着它一次又一次地发生。
We call it a menstrual cycle and it happens once, basically it's a process that takes
我们称之为月经周期，它基本上是一个过程，需要
28 days and it's the process of an egg coming down and either being fertilized or not.
28天，是卵子排出并是否受精的过程。
That's right.
没错。
So during ovulation, there is a certain period of time where it's precise for a woman to
所以在排卵期间，有一段时间是女性
be able to get pregnant, right?
最容易怀孕的，对吧？
And now what about when we move on to the men?
那接下来我们谈谈男性呢？
Now we talked about the women's side.
我们已经讲了女性这边。
What about the men's?
男性那边呢？
So basically women have eggs, men have sperm.
基本上女性有卵子，男性有精子。
Okay, these are little, they look like fish almost, they swim around and they are passed
好的，这些是小小的，它们看起来几乎像鱼，游来游去，通过
to a woman through semen and men have, I don't know, like 10 million of them or something
精液传递给女性，男性有，我不知道，大概一千万个之类的
crazy.
疯狂数量。
It's a huge amount of sperm.
那是大量的精子。
Now this is an interesting thing to differentiate.
这是一个有趣的区别点。
You said two things, sperm and semen, right?
你说了两个东西，精子和精液，对吧？
So sperm are the little creatures or little fish as you said that swim and semen is kind
所以精子是那些小生物或像你说的游动的小鱼，而精液是
of actually like the liquid that contains them.
实际上包含它们的液体。
That's right.
没错。
So it's almost not bigger than, but it's the liquid that they come in to basically attack
所以它差不多不比那个大，但它是它们用来攻击
an egg and try and fertilize an egg.
卵子并试图使卵子受精的液体。
And so remember in English, sperm can fertilize an egg, semen cannot.
所以记住在英语中，精子可以使卵子受精，精液不能。
And now this is interesting.
这很有趣。
We're talking about to fertilize.
我们在谈论“受精”。
Maybe we've heard this in gardening or something like this, we've heard a fertilizer.
也许我们在园艺之类的地方听过这个词，我们听过“肥料”。
But what do we mean by to fertilize or fertilization?
但“受精”或“受精作用”是什么意思呢？
Okay, basically fertilization or to fertilize something is to, in this case, put a sperm
好的，基本上受精或使某物受精，在这种情况下，就是把精子
together with an egg.
和卵子放在一起。
So to make a baby.
从而制造婴儿。
That's right.
没错。
And so an egg that is not fertilized will come down and will never become a baby.
所以未受精的卵子会排出，永远不会变成婴儿。
Because sperm, they don't find eggs and they just, you know, they die.
因为精子找不到卵子，它们就会，你知道，死掉。
Now there's another interesting word that's very related or close to this when we say
还有一个有趣的词，与这个非常相关或接近，当我们说
when a man or a woman is fertile.
一个男人或女人有生育能力时。
That's right.
没错。
So this only applies to women, not to men.
但这只适用于女性，不适用于男性。
You can say she's fertile.
你可以说她有生育能力。
That means she has eggs, her eggs come down and she can have a baby at some time.
这意味着她有卵子，她的卵子排出，她可以在某个时候生孩子。
But a woman who is infertile, she's not fertile, can never have babies.
但一个没有生育能力的女性，她不能生育，永远无法生孩子。
That's right.
没错。
So a lot of these women adopt babies.
所以很多这样的女性会领养孩子。
Now what about guys?
那男性呢？
You know that some men can't have babies as well.
你知道有些男性也无法生孩子。
Maybe their sperm is not very good or they have some, same thing, medical condition that
也许他们的精子质量不好，或者他们有某种，同样，医疗状况
prevents their sperm from fertilizing.
阻止他们的精子受精。
So you don't say that he is infertile or not fertile.
所以你不会说他不能生育或没有生育能力。
No, you don't.
不，你不会。
What do you say?
那你怎么说？
He is sterile.
他是不育的。
Okay.
好的。
So a woman can be fertile or infertile.
所以女性可以有生育能力或没有生育能力。
Infertile means she cannot have babies.
不孕意味着她无法生育孩子。
If a man's semen cannot fertilize an egg properly, he is called sterile.
如果男性的精液无法正常使卵子受精，他就被称为不育。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So this is all of what's going on inside the man's body as well.
所以这同样也是男性体内发生的一切。
And well, actually once they finally combine and get together and the sperm fertilize the
嗯，实际上，一旦它们最终结合并相遇，精子使卵子受精后，
egg, we have a little thing called an embryo.
我们就会得到一个叫做胚胎的小东西。
Okay, so obviously it doesn't become a baby for a little while.
好的，显然它不会立刻变成婴儿。
This is a point of contention, a point of argument for a lot of people because no one
这是一个争议点，对很多人来说是一个争论点，因为没有人
agrees when a baby becomes a baby.
同意婴儿何时成为婴儿。
But basically when an egg and a sperm come together, they create an embryo, which is
但基本上，当卵子和精子结合时，它们会形成一个胚胎，它
a combination of genetic information and tissue and all these things.
是遗传信息、组织等所有东西的结合体。
And that starts to grow and to become a fetus, which will one day when it is born, become
然后它开始生长，变成胎儿，最终在出生时，
a baby.
成为婴儿。
That's right.
没错。
So the embryo is basically the first stage of when the baby is forming.
所以胚胎基本上是婴儿形成的第一阶段。
But it's not really, as you said, this word fetus, it's not in our dialogue, but a fetus
但它并不完全是，如你所说，这个词“胎儿”不在我们的对话中，但胎儿
is actually a formed being, so to say, inside a woman's body, right?
实际上是一个已经成形的存在，可以说，在女性体内，对吧？
It's growing, it's starting to get the pieces that it needs to become a human being, but
它在生长，开始获得成为人类所需的部件，但
maybe has not fully developed yet.
可能还没有完全发育。
So it's still inside the woman's womb, we can say.
所以它仍然在女性的子宫内，我们可以这么说。
Very good.
非常好。
Okay, a lot of interesting things going on.
好的，这里有很多有趣的事情。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
我们不如再听一遍对话，然后回来再聊一会儿。
Continuing with our class, today we are going to study briefly the miracle of life.
继续我们的课程，今天我们将简要学习生命的奇迹。
Many of you may think you already know how babies come to be, but I'm sure that some
你们很多人可能觉得自己已经知道婴儿是怎么来的，但我相信今天我们要讨论的一些事情可能会让你们感到惊讶。
of the things we will be talking about today may surprise you.
今天我们要讨论的一些事情可能会让你们感到惊讶。
Billy, can you turn on the projector, please?
比利，请打开投影仪好吗？
Thanks.
谢谢。
Okay.
好的。
Does anyone know what this is?
有人知道这是什么吗？
It looks like a goat head to me.
在我看来它像个山羊头。
Nice try.
猜得不错。
But this is a woman's womb, which contains her uterus and ovaries.
但这是一个女人的子宫，里面包含她的子宫和卵巢。
The ovaries are packed with eggs and each month during the middle of the menstrual cycle,
卵巢里充满了卵子，每个月在月经周期的中期，
the ripest one will be sucked up by one of the fallopian tubes.
最成熟的那个会被一根输卵管吸走。
This is called ovulation and the exact time of ovulation depends on the length of a woman's
这叫做排卵，而排卵的具体时间取决于女性周期的长度。
cycle.
周期。
In an average 28-day cycle, ovulation will most likely happen between the 12th and 15th
在平均28天的周期中，排卵最可能发生在第12到第15天之间，
days, counting day one as the first day of your last period.
从你上次月经的第一天算起。
That's amazing.
太神奇了。
So each month the woman produces these eggs and then waits for them to be fertilized?
所以每个月女性都会产生这些卵子，然后等待它们受精？
Actually every woman is already born with over 400,000 eggs.
实际上，每个女性天生就拥有超过40万个卵子。
Some will start dying off immediately and others are released during her fertile period.
有些卵子会立即开始死亡，而另一些则会在她的生育期被释放出来。
What about the guys?
那男性呢？
I know they produce sperm and stuff.
我知道他们会产生精子和那些东西。
That's right.
没错。
The man's body has a tiny factory that produces sperm 24 hours a day.
男性的身体里有一个小工厂，每天24小时不停地生产精子。
Each ejaculation will release about 100 million sperm, so the factory is always pretty busy.
每次射精会释放大约1亿个精子，所以这个工厂总是很忙碌。
The sole purpose of a sperm's life is to fertilize the woman's egg.
精子生命的唯一目的就是让女性的卵子受精。
So then we basically need to put one and one together so we can have babies, right?
那么基本上我们只需要把两者结合起来就能生孩子，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
The man will have an orgasm during intercourse and ejaculate sperm and semen.
男性在性交过程中会达到高潮，并射出精子和精液。
Now this is where the race begins and all those millions of sperm will race and swim
现在，这就是比赛的开始，那数百万个精子会开始赛跑和游动，
from the cervix through the uterus and to the fallopian tubes.
从子宫颈穿过子宫，到达输卵管。
This could take anywhere from 45 minutes to 12 hours.
这个过程可能需要45分钟到12小时不等。
Not all of them make it since some of them go the wrong way and get lost or simply die.
并非所有精子都能成功，因为有些会走错路而迷路，或者干脆死掉。
Many will actually reach the egg but only one will penetrate it and fertilize it.
许多精子实际上会到达卵子，但只有一个能穿透并使其受精。
Once this happens, the egg instantly changes and creates a protective shield once the sperm
一旦发生这种情况，卵子会立即发生变化，并在精子安全进入后形成一道保护屏障。
is safely inside.
安全进入内部。
And then that's it?
然后就这样了？
Well the egg will be fertilized within about 24 hours of its release.
嗯，卵子在排出后大约24小时内就会受精。
The genetic material from the sperm combines with the genetic material in the egg to create
来自精子的遗传物质与卵子中的遗传物质结合，从而创造出
a new cell that will rapidly start dividing.
一个会迅速开始分裂的新细胞。
The woman is not actually pregnant until that bundle of new cells known as the embryo travels
这位女士实际上并没有怀孕，直到那团被称为胚胎的新细胞移动过来。
the rest of the way down the fallopian tube and attaches itself to the wall of her uterus.
在输卵管的剩余部分继续向下移动，并附着在子宫壁上。
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
Then let's move on.
那我们继续吧。
Alright so this whole aspect, we understand how the miracle of life works, right?
好了，关于这个方面，我们明白生命奇迹是如何运作的，对吧？
This is what it's called, having babies, the miracle of life.
这就是所谓的生儿育女，生命的奇迹。
It's even the name of a video we were forced to watch when I was 12 years old and I still
这甚至是我们12岁时被迫观看的一个视频的名字，我现在还记得。
have nightmares about.
做噩梦。
Well it is interesting, it is almost a miracle because you are basically creating something
嗯，这很有意思，几乎是个奇迹，因为你基本上是在创造某种东西。
out of nothing almost, right?
几乎毫无征兆，对吧？
That's right and what's amazing about it is that two people who have different genetic
没错，而且最神奇的是，两个基因不同的人
material and who have different experiences and who have different parts to their bodies
材料不同，经历不同，身体部位也不同。
come together and create something that's a combination of all those things.
融合在一起，创造出集所有元素于一体的东西。
So it's almost kind of like a game of surprise.
所以这几乎有点像一场惊喜游戏。
You don't know what's going to happen.
你不知道接下来会发生什么。
Are they going to have red hair or green eyes or are they going to be tall or short or fat
他们会有红头发还是绿眼睛？是高是矮还是胖？
or thin?
还是薄底？
It's interesting.
这很有意思。
Now talking about this aspect that you mentioned before, it's controversial when there is life
现在谈谈你之前提到的这个方面，当生命存在时，这个问题是有争议的。
or when if the embryo is a baby or it's not.
或者说胚胎是不是一个婴儿。
This is because of many countries or cities or states that are discussing the legalization
这是因为许多国家、城市或州正在讨论堕胎的合法化。
or not of abortions.
或者是否合法化。
That's right.
没错。
So the reason this is a problem for a lot of people is because no one agrees on when
所以这对很多人来说是个问题，因为没有人同意胎儿何时变成婴儿。
a fetus becomes a baby and so that will determine for a lot of people when it is okay to abort
而这将决定很多人认为何时可以堕胎。
the fetus or to kill it and when it is not.
或者杀死胎儿，以及何时不可以。
Because I've heard that some people say, well, in your first month, if you've already been
因为我听说有些人说，嗯，在你怀孕的第一个月，如果你已经怀孕一个月了。
pregnant for a month, the baby already has certain parts formed or even I think the heart
婴儿已经有某些部位形成了，甚至我认为心脏。
is beginning to form.
开始形成了。
So they say you're already pregnant.
所以他们说你已经怀孕了。
I mean, you already have a life inside you.
我的意思是，你体内已经有了一个生命。
Well, they say, well, no, it's actually after two months because then the baby has a heartbeat.
嗯，他们又说，不，实际上是在两个月后，因为那时婴儿有心跳了。
I'm not really sure about the timetables that I'm giving you.
我不太确定我给出的时间表。
I'm giving you more or less a rough outline, but this is the controversy.
我大致给你一个粗略的轮廓，但这就是争议所在。
That's right.
没错。
It affects laws in many countries.
它影响了许多国家的法律。
It affects what medical practitioners like doctors and nurses can do.
它影响了像医生和护士这样的医疗从业者能做什么。
And it's always, I think, been an issue as long as I've been alive.
而且我觉得，从我记事起，这一直就是个问题。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
Actually, the whole abortion topic is a big political debate between people who are against
实际上，整个堕胎话题是反对者和支持者之间的一场重大政治辩论。
it, who are in favor of it.
它，以及支持它的人。
So it's very interesting.
所以这非常有趣。
And actually, it's still very much illegal in many places in the world.
而且实际上，在世界许多地方，它仍然是非法的。
Absolutely.
绝对是这样。
And it changes, I think, according to where you are in America as well.
而且我认为，这在美国也因地区而异。
So some states have different laws about it, and some states are more lenient, for example.
所以有些州对此有不同法律，有些州则更宽松，比如。
And actually, this spawned a whole new controversy with the emergency pill, right?
而且实际上，这还引发了关于紧急避孕药的全新争议，对吧？
That basically, if you maybe are in risk of being pregnant, then you take this pill and
基本上，如果你可能面临怀孕风险，就吃这种药，
it kind of prevents fertilization.
它能在一定程度上阻止受精。
Or if fertilization occurred already, then it kind of prevents further growth of the
或者如果受精已经发生，它能在一定程度上阻止胚胎的进一步发育。
embryo.
胚胎。
Right.
对。
Basically, it's called the emergency contraceptive, and it's taken after you think you might be
基本上，它被称为紧急避孕药，是在你觉得自己可能怀孕后服用的。
pregnant.
怀孕。
But if you didn't use other contraceptives, like a condom, and you think maybe one of
但如果你没有使用其他避孕措施，比如避孕套，并且你作为女性觉得可能有一个卵子被精子受精了，它就会让你来月经。
your eggs as a woman was fertilized by sperm, it makes you have your period.
它让你来月经。
It makes you menstruate.
That means the lining of your uterus and any egg, even if it was fertilized, comes out.
这意味着你的子宫内膜和任何卵子，即使已经受精，都会排出体外。
And in some cases, people think of it as a kind of abortion.
在某些情况下，人们认为这类似于堕胎。
That's right.
没错。
So yeah, it's very interesting how the more that we understand about medicine and about
是的，很有意思，我们对医学了解得越多，
how life works, well, there have been advancements as well, like contraceptives that not only
生活就是这样，不过也有进步，比如避孕药，不仅
prevent unwanted pregnancies, but also prevent transmission of diseases, sexually transmitted
预防意外怀孕，同时也能预防疾病传播，尤其是性传播疾病。
diseases.
疾病。
That's right.
没错。
But at the same time, other things like this, like the emergency contraceptive and abortions
但同时，像紧急避孕药和堕胎这类事情
start popping up.
开始冒出来了。
So ethics.
所以，道德伦理。
Ethics, exactly.
伦理，没错。
So a very interesting topic, as we said, controversial, but at the same time, very much beautiful,
所以，一个非常有趣的话题，正如我们所说，有争议，但同时也很美。
because we are talking about how our bodies work and how everyone came to existence.
因为我们正在讨论人体如何运作，以及每个人是如何诞生的。
And how babies are born.
还有婴儿是怎么出生的。
Everyone loves babies.
大家都喜欢小宝宝。
That's right.
没错。
So we're really interested to get your insights, your opinion about anything that we've talked
所以我们真的很想听听你的见解，你对刚才讨论的任何话题的看法。
about today.
关于今天。
And if you have any other questions or comments, you can always reach us at EnglishPod.com.
如果你还有其他问题或意见，随时可以通过 EnglishPod.com 联系我们。
Yeah, we hope to see you there.
是的，我们希望能在那儿见到你。
And we hope this will start a nice conversation on our website.
我们希望这能在我们的网站上开启一段愉快的对话。
But remember, keep it clean.
但记住，保持文明。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So we'll see everyone there.
那我们到时候见大家。
Bye.
再见。
See you there.
那儿见。